# ERIK WAIBEL

# SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER

As a passionate and self-motivated lead software developer, I have 5+ years experience in creating production-ready web applications, with a focus on the latest frontend technologies. I increased EBIT by 30% while leading a team of 15+ software developers to a successful global production release for General Motors European brand sites. I helped reduce our team's development time by 20% with implementation of Git flow methodology and best practices. I have strong communication skills and can thrive under any high pressure environment.

■ ejwaibel+resume@gmail.com

**J** +1 480-331-1899

**♀** Chandler, AZ

• https://www.github.com/ejwaibel

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ejwaibel

### **SKILLS**

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, NodeJS, REST
- Strong knowledge and experience with modern JavaScript frameworks (Angular, Vue.js, Backbone, Ember etc.)
- Proficient with SCSS/LESS/PostCSS, ES6, Grunt, Gulp, Yeoman, PHP, Webpack, Web Components
- Advanced shell script development using Perl, bash, ksh
- Strong knowledge and experience with Angular, React, Vue.js, Express, MongoDB
- Experience with DevOps, Docker, AWS, Jenkins

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Lead Frontend Engineer | Senior Vue Developer

**iRELO** 

04/2018 - Present

Lead frontend engineer/architect responsible for building and maintaining 10 single page web applications utilizing Vue and Nuxt.

- · Architect custom VueJS components and integrate with new and existing applications across organization
- Practice tuning and maximizing performance of application and understanding of patterns and practices
- · Utilized vue-cli 3.0 integration to perform JavaScript compilation and minification for all frontend development
- Created multiple components and sites from InVision UX designs
- Coordinate with PM in Asana agile methodology to ensure all bugs & features are completed on time
- · Generated global custom eslint and stylelint configurations for inclusion with all company projects
- Organized Git standardization and process through Gitlab, while training and supporting developers
- Produced Git CLI script to generate automatic changelog and Gitlab release
- Integrated latest JavaScript standards and ES2017 features

## **Adjunct Faculty**

#### Chandler Gilbert Community College

01/2018 - Present

Adjunct faculty in the Computer Information Systems department with a focus on web development courses integrating HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.

# Lead UI Engineer | Senior Web Developer

#### General Motors IT

07/2014 - 04/2018

Lead UI engineer responsible for end to end feature enablement across the UI layer, and the integration of UI into the broader ecosystem of General Motors brand websites. Lead a team of 15 developers to increase their knowledge and performance within a fast paced development environment.

- Applied CSS3 styles to modular components based on PSD styleguides
- Engineered robust, scalable and extendable JavaScript
- Built multiple angular applications for inclusion into a Bootstrap/Foundation framework
- Designed solution for custom SCSS inheritance to accommodate multiple shared projects
- Arhitected internal modular JavaScript solution with TerrificJS called "AtomicJS"
- Lead team of 20 developers to deliver 65 custom AEM components for the European brands release, which reached 20 different countries
- Built custom solution for Gulp build process and provided enhancements based on project challenges
- Integrated custom jQuery plugins into project's custom AtomicJS framework
- Triaged bugs on a daily basis to ensure issues are resolved in time for production release
- Coordinated with business and design teams to ensure proper requirements for new features
- Researched advanced CSS & JavaScript techniques to implement latest browser features and enhance the customer's experience
- · Performed Subversion and Git operations within a development and production environment

## Software Engineer II

iTRACS / Commscope

09/2012 - 07/2014

Responsible for the construction and implementation of an enterprise class web application providing business critical datacenter management solution. Lead developer for design and implementation of customer portal with multiple WordPress instances. Worked closely with team members in an agile environment to ensure implementation of features/functionality conform to release/business objectives.

- Created and deployed advanced RESTful API interfaces with PHP and SOAP
- · Developed and maintained a large responsive single-page application supported on all major browsers and mobile devices
- Designed and developed advanced RESTful API interfaces with PHP and SOAP Web Services
- Extended existing jQuery UI widgets with custom component widgets
- Performed Subversion and Git operations within a development and production environment
- · Assisted in managing Git merge requests with multiple developers and branches through Gitlab
- Managed product enhancements and defects timely in an agile development process
- Cooperated with QA to release the initial version of customer-facing single-page web application on time with a team of three web developers and two web designers.

## Adjunct Faculty

#### Art Institute of Phoenix

09/2010 - 12/2014

Adjunct professor for Graphic & Web Design department, with average class size of 12 students.

- 1. Intro to Programming
- 2. Intro / Intermediate / Advanced Scripting
- 3. Intro / Intermediate / Advanced Authoring
- 4. User Centered Design

#### Owner | Consultant | Software Developer

Everything Just Works, LLC

05/2010 - 10/2013

Everything Just Works, LLC focused on giving computer users a one-on-one interaction with computer repair gurus. You should be able to understand your computer and have the best experience possible. We want to empower individuals to use the computer to its full potential and be aware of the problems that can arise so that they aren't stuck paying someone to recover their data.

- Built custom website for Realty Company that would allow users to search for houses based on a given MLS listing.
  - PHP application with IIS 7.5 and Microsoft SQL 2008 database
  - Object Oriented PHP5 from scratch with IIS 7.5 and MSSQL 2008 integration.
  - Developed custom JavaScript algorithm with Google Maps API to calculate distances between multiple addresses
  - Built custom jQuery plugin to generate tabular data records
- Developed the "Conditional Questions" add-on using PHP & ¡Query for the Event Espresso WordPress plugin.
- Diagnosed and repaired local and small business websites that use WordPress.
- Improved and resolved problems for WordPress websites with custom PHP, jQuery, CSS, and HTML due to incompatible WordPress theme(s) and/or client requests.
- · Eradicated viruses and malware from infected computers after performing necessary troubleshooting techniques.

#### Software Developer

Insight Global, Contract w/Level 3 Communications

07/2012 - 10/2012

- Developed the internal website on Apache server for network planners using Perl Mason, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, and CSS3.
- Configured and administered Bugzilla installation on Linux CentOS server for customer required bug tracking system.
- Provided multiple Perl script reports that would run on a daily/weekly cron job and generate custom Excel spreadsheets for client.
- Created custom internal Perl modules to help with database connections, common utility functions, and Excel spreadsheet customization.

## Systems Engineer

APEX Systems, Contract w/Wells Fargo

10/2011 - 06/2012

- Developed Perl script that would run as a daemon to search specific directories for files.
- Customized in-house Perl modules for better functionality and maintainability.
- Extended Perl scripts to help automate tasks across 15 UNIX Solaris and Linux servers, including threads that would run commands on specified servers in parallel.
- Enhanced current scripts to include the use of Log::Log4Perl in order to generate log files for all output in order to verify steps were completed successfully.
- · Provided multi-level support to the Customer Care team and employees that worked directly with Wells Fargo Wholesale customers.

#### Software Developer | SCM Consultant

A Better Solution, Inc.

04/2007 - 06/2011

- Implemented Perl scripts to help developers integrate with ClearCase more seamlessly.
- Developed Perl modules for custom ClearCase functionality within our scripts. This allowed to easily and quickly building Perl scripts for custom ClearCase interaction.
- Ensured project builds and releases performed efficiently and correctly through the use of IBM Rational BuildForge.
- Produced automated build scripts using Perl and shell programming.
- Administered UNIX & Windows machines for the IT group whenever necessary.
- Provided first level technical assistance to end users including, but not limited to: replicating errors, resolving application issues, and investigating errors.

## Jr. PHP Developer

#### BlueHornet.com

09/2006 - 04/2007

Junior PHP developer helping to enhance the existing web application with custom Object Oriented code for quicker development and easier maintainability. Coordinated with the graphic design team and integrated Photoshop layouts using HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. Documented new features thoroughly for use with customer support documentation.

## **EDUCATION**

#### B.S., Computer Science

California State Polytechnic University

09/2001 - 08/2006

Erik Waibel — 480-331-1899 — ejwaibel+resume@gmail.com